Finding Aid for Natural Resources of Michigan Web Archive
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Natural Resources of Michigan Web Archive 2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library.
2014025 Aa 3
Web collection of websites created by various organizations whose service is to natural resources of the State of Michigan, archived by the Bentley Historical Library using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010.
14 web sites online; multiple captures
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Websites gathered beginning in 2010 using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service web crawler.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michigan's natural resources are among Bentley Historical Library's important topical collections priorities. The topic's priority is based on the Bentley Library's mission as established by the University of Michigan Board of Regents to document "the state, its institutions, and its social, economic, and intellectual development," the historical collecting patterns of the library, and overall collection development priorities in all formats. The process of setting collecting priorities is described by Christine Weideman's "A New Map for Field Work: Impact of Collections Analysis on the Bentley Historical Library" (American Archivist, Winter 1991, Vol. 54 Issue 1, pp. 54-60.) and Judith E. Endelman's "Looking Backward to Plan for the Future: Collection Analysis for Manuscript Repositories." (American Archivist, Summer 1987, Vol. 50 Issue 3, pp. 340-355.)
In selecting web content for permanent preservation, the Bentley Historical Library seeks:
Websites of organizations or individuals whose archives the Library is committed to preserve.
Website that fill gaps in existing collections.
Websites with unique content that documents the work and/or thought process of a person or organization.
Websites that periodically incorporate new content or feature regular updates.
Websites with content that is not likely to be duplicated in an individual or organization's paper records.
As of 2013, the Bentley Library will concentrate efforts on documenting activities of Michigan's organizations and movements concerned with the State's natural resources, conservation and protection of Michigan's waterways, land, flora and fauna. In addition to these priorities, the MHC remains open to the consideration of material with great research potential in any area of Michigan's natural resources.
To learn more about the Bentley Historical Library's Web Archives visit http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/index.php.
The Web Archive of Michigan's Natural Resources collection contains archived websites created by various organizations and movements concerned with preservation of natural resources in the State of Michigan. The websites have been archived by the Bentley Historical Library, using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler beginning in 2010. Access to all websites archived by the Bentley Historical Library is available at: http://bentley.umich.edu/dchome/webarchives/index.php.
Web Archives include websites of conservation groups, environmental organizations and nature associations who call the state of Michigan home. The collection is especially strong in documenting conservation initiatives and environmental protection in Michigan.
The year that appears next to the website title in the contents list indicates the date that the website was first archived. Archived versions of the site from later dates may also be available.
Subjects:
East Michigan Environmental Action Council.; Ecology Center of Ann Arbor.; Environmental Fund (U.S.); Federation for American Immigration Reform.; Friends of the Jordan River Watershed.; Huron River Watershed Council.; Little Traverse Conservancy.; Michigan Audubon Society.; Michigan Environmental Council.; Michigan Garden Clubs.; Michigan Land Use Institute.; Michigan Natural Areas Council.; Michigan Nature Association.; Sierra Club. Michigan Chapter.; Michigan United Conservation Clubs.; Michigan. Wilderness and Natural Areas Advisory Board.; Northern Michigan Planned Parenthood.; Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore Advisory Commission.; West Michigan Environmental Action Council.; Zero Population Growth, Inc.; Birds--Michigan.; Birth control.; Cities and towns--Growth--Michigan.; Citizens' associations--Michigan.; Commerce and industry.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan, Northern.; Conservation projects (Natural resources)--Michigan, Northern.; Ecology--Michigan.; Energy conservation--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan, Northern.; Environmental protection--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Environmental protection--United States.; Gardening--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Hazardous wastes--Michigan.; Immigrants--United States.; Land use--Michigan.; Land use--Michigan--Planning.; Natural areas--Michigan.; Natural areas--Michigan, Northern.; Natural resources.; Nature centers--Michigan, Northern.; Nature conservation--Michigan, Northern.; Outdoor recreation--Michigan.; Pesticides--Environmental aspects--Michigan.; Politics and public policy.; Recycling (Waste, etc.)--Michigan.; Refuse and refuse disposal--Michigan.; Salvage (Waste, etc.)--Michigan.; Water--Michigan.; Water conservation--Michigan, Southeastern.; Water rights--Michigan.; Water-supply--Michigan, Southeastern.; Watershed management--Michigan--Jordan River Watershed (Antrim County and Charlevoix County); Wetland conservation--Michigan.; Wetlands--Michigan.; Wildlife conservation--Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; Women in Michigan.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Antrim County (Mich.); Charlevoix County (Mich.); East Jordan (Mich.); Great Lakes (North America)--Environmental conditions.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Huron River Watershed (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Jordan River Watershed (Antrim County and Charlevoix County, Mich.); United States--Emigration and immigration.
Contributors:
North Woods Call.
Genre Terms:
Blogs.; Websites.
- Natural Resources of Michigan Web Archives
  - East Michigan Environmental Action Council 2012
  - Ecology Center 2012
  - Friends of the Jordan River Watershed 2012
  - Huron River Watershed Council 2012
  - Little Traverse Conservancy 2012
  - Michigan Audubon Society 2012
  - Michigan Environmental Council 2012
  - Michigan Garden Clubs 2012
  - Michigan Land Use Institute 2012
  - Michigan Nature Association 2012
  - Michigan United Conservation Clubs 2012
  - North Woods Call 2012
  - Sierra Club Michigan Chapter 2012
  - West Michigan Environmental Action Council 2012